Members present.
Of course, I can see,
Jim Halsey.
Here.
Ed Smith.
Edmund Smith present?
Yeah, present.
Okay.
Let's see who else is there.
Jed Larson?
Yep, here.
>> Okay.
My screen
just lost you, so I don't know where you are. But
I guess we have a quorum,
and we don't have any
alternates to be seated,
so we can proceed
with the meeting.
Do we have any need to make additions or changes to the agenda?
Seeing none, we will go on to agenda item four, public comment.
Who's administering this meeting, by the way? I am, Linda. Okay, Linda.
I'll count on you to
recognize whoever may wish to speak and to
appropriately unmute them for that purpose. Okay.
>> I
want to put a shout out to Jed for a moment.
Are you there, Jed? Yep.
I made you co host.
So
can you help
George if there's any documents from the website that have to be screen shared?
Okay, Linda, I I have got to the the home page there, so I should be able to help out on that. Okay, I appreciate it. I'm working off two computers here so it's kind of hard for me to do it. So Megan, Amanda
asked if I would, you know, reach out to you
to help.
We'll see how effective her training was.
Okay.
>> Hope it all works.
Okay, so we've got that settled
then. We can then proceed
to
agenda item number five,
approval of minutes.
I would like a motion to approve the minutes of the 07/14/2020
regular meeting.
>> I'd
like to move to
approve minutes of the July 14 meeting.
Ed Smith seconds the motion.
>> Okay. So motion by Jim Halsey, second by Ed Smith to approve the minutes. Any discussion?
They are long.
Hi.
We
just had
>> two people that were in attendance that weren't on the agenda
Bill and Donna Phillips that's all okay
>> Okay, those corrections will be noted. Any other
corrections,
edits?
Okay, seeing none, I'll call for a vote on motion.
And we'll do it by a roll call again.
Jim Hallisey?
Aye.
Jed Larson?
>> Are you able to hear me, George? I can hear you. Okay, I was trying to make a comment before you moved to voting
>> on it. Oh, well, didn't, that I didn't hear.
Were you muted at the time or?
>> Sure, but
the comment's just a typo on page three,
paragraph H, third line down
needs a two in front of the year we've got the 06/21/2020
instead of 2020.
Okay, got it.
And now I vote to approve.
Aye. Okay.
>> Thank you. So
we're
voting on the minutes as corrected.
Ed Smith. Aye.
And
Vice
Chairman George Eliot votes aye.
So the motion carries four-zero-zero.
Okay,
next item on the agenda,
administrative approvals.
So far we see none,
unless,
Mr. Wagner or were there any other
administrative actions that we need to be aware of?
>> No,
I haven't been appointed to approve anything yet, so.
>> Nothing yet. Well, that simplifies.
Okay, I'm working on two screens here too, folks. So you'll forgive me if I seem distracted.
Okay, so item seven on the agenda, permit applications.
The first
on the agenda is IWWC
twenty twenty one from Emmanuel Correa. And of course,
Jerry Hardisty is the
engineer
for
the
subdivision in residential construction
at 12 West Shore Lane
in BoltonAndover
Connecticut.
Let's see now I believe we have some updates on that
and I guess I can call on
Mr. Hardisty to
comment on the revisions that were
submitted
along with the letter that we received
today
so Jerry can you unmute or can somebody unmute Jerry for I
>> don't think I'm muted but
I was hoping to
see the drawings that I submitted today, if we
can bring those up.
Unfortunately, was not able to make the last inland wetlands meeting,
but I got the minutes from that and I saw that there were a number of comments from both the reviewing engineer and the
wetlands commission.
I have tried to address
all of those comments with
a revised plan.
And actually, it's not even a revised plan so much as
it is the actual subdivision plans
that will be submitted to planning and zoning,
and that takes care of the inconsistency
concern that
Jed had,
a valid concern. We didn't know which ones you were looking at.
But so
I've submitted
the subdivision and development plans for this,
and
these plans should
address
the comments that were
that were
covered in the review comments and the Commission's comments.
>> Judd, can you screen share those documents? I have them.
I'm bringing them up on my own desktop but I can't share
so if we want to have
>> I can I can also make you a co host too if you want George
>> it wouldn't work because I'm working on two computers and the
Zoom is not Okay? My
>> Gary, which one do you want to see? Do you want to see the development plan or the subdivision plan? The development plan is probably more
instructive.
Okay.
Do you see that one there, Jed?
What's
the full title of that document?
A site plan 8,220.
So is the subdivision plan up there now?
>> Don't see yet. He's looking for the development plan.
The one right above it that says 8220 development.
Okay. That should be it.
No.
>> So what are you seeing from me? We're just seeing you. Okay.
Here we go. Voila.
Here it is.
Thanks, Jed. Yep.
>> Okay.
This plan
this is the plan that will be submitted to Planning and Zoning.
This development plan includes a soil erosion and sediment control plan
as
in
accordance with the 2002 Connecticut
guidelines for soil erosion and sediment control.
That was one of the comments that should be followed.
I've extended silt fence the entire length of the
disturbed area between the disturbed area and the wetlands as requested.
Another significant factor is that I've switched the
the
septic system reserve and proposed
primary system. So the primary system now is farther from
the wetlands than the
reserve area.
As I've stated before, it would be my preference to put the primary area
closer to the wetlands because the soils are better. They're a little steeper there,
and it would be a better situation for
the septic system.
There was a
comment that I needed to show a 100 foot regulated area.
That was on there before,
but it may not have been showing up.
Anyway, this is a if you can see my cursor,
this is a regulated area for the western pockets of wetlands and this is the regulated area for the
Eastern wetlands.
Not sure what else there was a comment about
not
directing
runoff into the wetlands to the west.
The general topo for this property is running north to south or south to north, excuse me. So the chances of directing flow
to that wetlands is pretty minimal.
There was another question
in the review comments about whether or not the
western pockets of wetlands were a vernal pool,
and I discussed that with my soil scientist today
and he said that there was no way to really
verify that for sure without doing a
year long monitoring of it and seeing the reactions in the springtime.
However, he doubted that it was a vernal pool. I can tell you that area has been disturbed over the years because
where the
where you can see I have the lot one placard on this thing used to be a fairly significant
horse barn.
And the area behind the horse barn,
they piled manure
and
did other agricultural things in this area.
So it is some it is disturbed,
and
I don't think there will be any more disturbance.
It being on the property line
and over to the west side, I think,
help mitigate
any chances of that area being disturbed further.
I think that
I honestly think that this development,
one lot development, can be done with with virtually no impact on the wetlands at all.
There's an existing fence right now at the edge of the clearing,
and that fence, the tree line is right up against that fence, and it
provides a pretty significant buffer between any development or any land use and the wetlands.
Anything else? Can try to answer questions.
But that's it in a nutshell.
>> Do any commissioners have any questions or comments
on the
site plan that has been presented and revised and on Jerry's comments?
>> Jerry, wasn't one of the comments that
to take a look at repositioning the house to the Southwest
so that it would be outside of the
upland review area?
>> That
was a comment, Jed. And I'll tell you what, this
I wanted to leave this here because I thought that, first of all, I think that this is the most appropriate location for the house so that we don't crowd the back
property line and get nearer to neighbors there.
And also that if we provided it here, the house that I've got on this drawing is just a potential house. You know, it's we don't have house plans for anything.
And so I figured if I showed this, then the commission could approve this based on nothing would be any closer than this point. But certainly,
we could move it back and farther from the wetlands with
a new application, with the actual
plot plan that would have to be submitted before any kind of
a building approval.
>> Yeah. This is Jim Hallessey, and I'd like to weigh in from a zoning perspective. The the
rear yard setback is actually 50 feet,
and that would preclude moving the house
back much further. I mean, there's some room, but
right now it's shown as a 20 foot rear yard.
It's gonna have to be changed.
It's not gonna impact the the plan
before you.
It just would prohibit
moving the house much further back.
>> Understand,
but isn't one of the requirements that we
see what the alternate
less
invasive
options might be so that the Commission can make the proper
decision on that?
And
both Mr. Bruner and the engineer
talked,
I think, about moving
it out of the Upland review area.
>> Jed, if we moved it if we moved it south and west, we would be in a different Upland review area. We're we're kind of
there's not a whole lot of room here.
>> And I don't want it to
This to go into
a
zoning discussion per se.
But I think if there's an option
that shows the house
out of the Upland review area,
and again having the wrong setback on the map might preclude that
from
being able to see that,
I think we owe it to ourselves to see what those options are and there may be,
you know, one of the things that you're supposed to do in the plan is provide the rationale for why we chose not to
pursue those options.
But we're not giving the Commission the opportunity to see if there's a better way to do it because we're only looking at one that you consider the worst case scenario.
>> I don't know how to address that, Chad.
If you think that it's necessary to have 85 foot clearance instead of 75 foot clearance from the wetlands, you
can certainly make that a condition of approval.
But again, my position is that
this house and the development of this house would have
no impact at all on this wetlands.
>> Okay,
well I just
it seems to me that we have
not
done what our procedure requires to provide the alternatives,
and we've not done what you were asked to do by Hank Gruner
and
the engineer who looked at it.
>> Well, those comments, I
saw, says to rotate the house.
Rotation of the proposed house. As I said, rotating the house in the position that it's in
would
I don't know how you could do that and still
and gain a whole lot.
>> Okay. But I yeah. I've made my point.
And I guess I will address it from a zoning perspective a little bit.
When we were looking at the
drawing before, I don't think we had the 100
foot regulated area on the Western Wetlands in there.
And I think there's
probably
a zoning,
a subdivision regulation that may preclude
having,
I know we talked about the septic,
I think that paragraph in the subdivision rigs may specify a well and house as well. And so I was trying to get a
feel for something that complied with
outside
the review area
and then
make your case for thinking that this is a better plan?
>> Well, well can go just about anywhere. We can move the well to right behind the house
where at least 25 feet radius is is not within any kind of a wetland setback area.
>> Jim Halsey.
Gary,
through the chair.
Why do you show two radiuses for the well?
>> Because
the
inside radius, the 25 foot radius is because you can't be within any kind of drains.
So if you have it near the house, you need to show the 25 foot radius so that you know you're outside of the
influence of the footing drains around the house.
Okay.
>> And the outer
radius, of course, is the 75 feet
that we need to be away from any septic
part of the septic system.
Right.
I believe it's a 100 feet for subdivision right?
Yes.
>> Well, if this were a live meeting, I would sketch a new rectangular house right in this area and
ask the commission if they could approve that.
But I can't do that from here.
>> Ed Smith, are you talking about rotating the house
clockwise?
>> I
would suggest to rotate the house counterclockwise
because
we want the
face of the house
towards the road.
So I would put the back of the house more or less
coincidental with this contour line.
>> Let me interject here. Jerry, you want to
can you share your desktop? And let me I'll make you a co host to share your desktop.
Because, of course, we cannot see we're looking at Judd's desktop
the plan
and of course your cursor and his are not in sync so I'm jabbering
away here meaninglessly okay
there's
something left out yes
>> Okay. So do you want me to make Jerry a co host?
>> If you can do that now, yes. That way he could share his
I just managed to annotations.
>> I just click on share screen? Yeah. Jed, can you take your screen down? Okay.
Jed, would you be able to walk Jerry through on the next step to screen share?
Do I just click on the share screen?
Yes.
Whiteboard.
There you go.
There's nothing on my whiteboard.
No.
Can you guys see my screen now?
Not yet.
Not
me.
I just opened a screen from my desktop.
Can't see, Jerry.
>> Is your document that you wanna open on your desktop? How's this? Can you see this? Go. Good. Yep. You're good. So
>> this
is from my desktop,
but it should be the same drawing that we've been looking at.
Appears to be.
>> Okay. So
I guess my point is that
or my discussion is that
we could pull this building back and put the backside of the building more or less parallel
with this contour line.
And that would provide us the most
clearance
from the regulated
area.
>> Yeah, this is Jim. Just want make a comment. I
mean, the further you move that house back, the longer that driveway is. Yeah.
It can impact.
>> So you've got more runoff, you've more nitrates coming off. Yeah, get more
pervious surface.
Duration.
>> So essentially we're looking at several trade offs
in terms of
the
foundation location
in terms of,
I think you mentioned already,
Jerry,
the
setback from the rear of the lot and proximity to neighbors.
Jim mentioned
just now
a longer driveway
to access
the
site.
And
with consequence, depending on the driveway is constructed,
could be
a larger impact, although again it's within the upland review area, not
within the wetland per se.
So are there any other considerations
that we have missed?
Since Jed Larson brought up the question,
I'll ask him
directly if he has any comments
on the discussion so far. Is this a
satisfactory
explication
of the conditions
that you were
raising?
>> Well
I did not have an awful lot of time
to
understand
what documents we were going to be looking at tonight because they were just recently added to the website.
I was expecting
to see a proposal
where we placed the house outside of the 100 foot
upland review area because our procedure,
the wetlands procedure,
specifies that alternatives considered and subsequently rejected by the applicant,
which would cause less or no environmental impact to wetlands or water courses,
and why the alternative is set forth in the application was chosen,
all such alternatives shall be diagrammed on a site plan or drawing.
Now when we look at the design criteria for a lot,
it says a subdivision
lot
should be designed such that no proposed locations of sanitary waste disposal,
wells,
buildings, or other structures
shall be within 100 feet of the one hundred year
flood high plane or the wetland review area.
And so that's what I was looking for.
>> Jerry, do you think it's possible to address
Judd's concerns
now? Or is this going to have to require further
consideration?
>> I
think it would
be difficult to locate
all the house septic and well outside of the 100 foot setback.
I think we could do it, but I don't think it would be the best design.
We could rotate this so that the garage is forward,
the house is behind it, and
the well is behind.
The well could be over in this corner here.
So, yeah, it could be done.
And I guess at this point,
like I said, I was trying to show what would be the most likely and most attractive setup for this particular lot without having the house jammed way back and extending the driveway.
But
again, I
feel that this is a responsible design, that it's not going to affect the wetlands.
But if you
if you would approve this conditionally on the on the.
Commissioner
requirement that the House and the well are outside of the 100 foot setback I could make that happen.
In which case, of course, then the only thing you'd be ruling on is the position of the driveway.
And something like that could be once I
redraw this and submit it, that's something that
mister
Wagner could probably review and okay because it's a matter of seeing if it fits. Yeah.
>> I don't I don't have that authority yet.
I haven't been authorized as a as a agent yet, so I I would be unable to approve it. Okay. Well
>> I can see gets point. I mean, he wants to see it. He doesn't want to try and visualize.
>> Right. Right. No, I would make these I would make these revisions upon the conditional approval, then I'd make the final revisions and submit that.
>> I think we as a commission need to see it. That's what our procedures
require.
This is Kevin Arneson. I have a question.
I'm sorry. Who was asking to speak here? This
is Jason Pabri, owner.
>> Okay. I'm afraid we can't
take your input at this point.
That would be a public comment.
It's a public comment.
We're not in
a hearing
right now. We're in a meeting.
Okay.
Okay, I'd like to
come to some
resolution,
at least temporary resolution on this.
We have other items on the agenda.
And I think our options right now
include a
Jerry pointed out, a conditional
approval, that is approval
of the application with conditions
that would have to be met
before
any
work could be before any of the work could be undertaken.
We could
table the discussion.
We have I believe on this
we have a total of I'm
not doing the math too quickly but it looks like we have another 30 about another 30
for action on this
item.
So
I will
ask the commissioners
what their pleasure is on how to proceed
here.
Do we want to entertain a motion to
approve
the
permit application
with conditions
or do we want to table
>> George this is Linda yeah
I'm looking at your calendar and your next meeting is September
15,
which is more than thirty days out.
>> Okay. Would it be more than ninety days out from
the deadline?
>> The
deadline was 06/10.
So I think it would be more than ninety days.
>> Which means we'd have to have a special meeting if if we defer action.
Right.
>> Okay,
I'd rather
not put us in a position where we have to have a special meeting
just for this application.
So I think it would be preferable if we could
get some
resolution
on the application
of tonight's meeting.
And in that case,
what we'll need is a motion
to
approve
with conditions,
or we could have a motion to reject or
however the commissioners wish to
frame that motion.
I think from my point of view, best
would be to
a motion to approve with conditions.
>> Okay, I just have a procedural question.
If
motion to approve is
put forth
and the consensus
is the
commission
would feel more comfortable with seeing
revisions
discussed.
The application if we voted on that in that motion, it would would be effectively
denying the application.
So the alternative would be Once
we vote, it's denied.
I just wanted to
not go down the road. We can't back out here.
>> I think the applicant has the authority to request a sixty five day extension,
which is on top of the 90 degrees
that the governor has
granted due to the
pandemic?
>> Well if that's the case then we would have time to
view and consider
alternatives
proposed alternatives.
And again I don't think that
the
the question here is not
whether we need to
have a revised plan but whether we are looking at a plan
that
considers alternatives.
>> I think if we had a revised plan, it needs to have the correct setback
at the rear of the lot.
>> I'm sorry, what was the issue with the
setback at the rear?
>> This drawing shows a 20 foot rear setback.
I think Jim
said it was 50. I don't have the chart in front of me, but I know it's not 20.
>> Yeah, I did look it up right before the meeting. I thought it was 50 and in fact it is 11.2
of the regulations,
11.2.
Alright. I personally don't have a problem with with
the plan as it's shown. But I do embrace
Jed's point. I can't see structuring
an approval
that would address
the concern.
I
mean, you're trying to structure,
you're asking for somebody to review a plan that isn't there.
I'm having a hard time picture personally.
Okay then, should we
>> Let
me just say one more thing. This
plan
is not significantly different than the one that was initially submitted, except for that we did revise
the locations of the proposed septic system
and the reserve area.
We did that and that revised the that necessarily revised the driveway, which puts the driveway closer to the wetlands.
So I would suggest that we have shown at least a couple of different
scenarios
here.
Again, I'm trying to present something that's going to be the most valuable to
whomever buys this lot.
I think that typically the house is facing the road and
to make something way back just adds additional driveway and makes it a less attractive
piece of property.
At the initial submission of this thing, this Commission
ruled that this would not be a significant activity.
So I'm not sure
why this would be
not approvable.
>> Ed Smith, Commissioner, I'm wondering,
would I be breaking protocol
to
ask the owner
to comment at this time? Earlier, he had tried to comment, but it wasn't appropriate. Can a commissioner ask them to comment? This is not an owner. This is in a butter.
Thank
you.
>> I will tell you that the proximity to the neighborhood houses was one of the reasons that this house is located where it is.
>> Well, Ed Smith again. Could the buyer comment? Could a commissioner ask for the buyer to comment? Perhaps the buyer has something to say that will speed this up.
>> I
don't know what that means. There's no buyer that I'm aware. So who was trying to speak earlier?
But they weren't permitted from the public.
>> An abutting
landowner.
Folks we really do need to move along on this. And I think Jerry's point is well taken that
he has addressed concerns
previously
raised
and
argues that
although
we're
within an upland review area
the proposed activity
will not have any
measurable impact
on the
wetlands
of concern.
And
I really think that we need to either, as they say, fish or cut bait here
and
either
you know
insist on a new plan
or
vote on what we have on the permit
application that we have in front of us.
Either way we need a motion
to take action.
So is anyone prepared
to make a motion
either to
act on the permit
or the permit application
or
to
request the applicant
allow
further time for consideration
and postpone it till our next meeting.
>> Jim Halsey,
with a question. Is
there a,
are there conditions
prepared
to go to company
for approval?
That's something that we
just wouldn't have.
>> This is Linda. As far as I know, the answer is no.
Okay. Thank you.
>> Okay. So
the applicant's looking for direction. I mean,
I'm concerned about also procedurally,
there's four of us,
which means that ties a denial, I believe.
That's correct.
>> Okay.
I'm gonna make a motion. I don't think
which way to
get it out there.
If we make a motion to
table it,
and that
fails,
then it seems we have to act
we have to then act on it
act on an approval.
Correct.
>> Okay.
So I'm going to motion that we
table it
and ask
applicant
to
provide
the alternatives
spelled out in
the regulations
and ask agent to prepare
a draft approval or conditions that would accompany the summary.
>> Okay,
we have a motion
to table
discussion
of the further discussion
of the
permit application
and conditions
to be imposed on the applicant
for
review by the Commission.
Do we have a second for that motion?
Jed seconds.
>> Okay, so a motion to table by Jim Hallisey,
second by Jed Larson.
I
don't think that's a debatable,
so we will proceed to a vote on the motion.
Again, we'll have to do this by roll call.
And
from
on my screen, the
first up is Jim Halsey.
>> Commissioner Eliade, I do have one concern. We do not have a request for an extension at this time. What's that? We do not have the request for an extension at this time.
>> Well, if we don't get that request, we'll have to have a special meeting.
>> Okay.
Roll
call. Yeah, roll call. Let me go aye. You called my name. I'm going say aye. Okay.
>> Commissioner Larson.
Aye.
Commissioner Smith.
And Vice
Chairman Elliott
voting aye. So the motion to table carries four-zero-zero.
Okay we
can I think eliminate Jerry's screen
from our desktops?
The next item on the agenda.
IWC
twenty-twenty
three
application for new residential
construction upland review area and modification of a floodplain
at 57
Hendee Road, Alphagans William PR
and Donna J Phillips.
And I believe Mr. Bushnell, the engineer,
is also present.
Okay
yes
alrighty
so where do we stand on this one
>> Well, the way I see it, we submitted a updated plan last Tuesday
to the wetlands commission and to the engineering viewing Brandon Anfield.
I believe all the,
bequests from Brandon were covered
on that plan. They were actually covered on the plan before that I think that you guys saw last month.
So,
I think everything was covered on the plan. I did not hear back from Brandon. I contacted him this afternoon after lunch just to follow-up.
And
he said he did. He had meant to call me Friday but didn't.
He just said everything was good. He wanted
response
to his three comments,
which I haven't had time to do. Was kind of, you know, stuck with time being it was this afternoon I talked to him in meetings tonight. And
then we started discussing
about the fill and the compensation
needed for the, you know, filling the floodplain
and taking the fill from the other area on the property.
We started talking about the amount of fill and how we could
potentially
reduce the impact on the wetlands over on the west side of the property,
taking the fill out over there. And we both came to the conclusion that we only needed to fill
to the flood elevation, the fill put into the flood elevation, which is three twenty three five in the house area,
only that amount needed to be taken out on the other side.
You know, originally we had figured 600 yards of fill to complete that house development project.
Now I'm down in the neighborhood of 400.
Just to fill up to the flood elevation and then the 200 above that could come from off-site or anywhere else.
You know,
actually Mr. Phillips has some, fill stockpiled
from the 57 Hendrie Road house. Just recently completed a, septic repair on that house, because that septic was substandard there.
So working with the health district, they ended up removing
some fill. It wasn't
useful for the septic area.
And he still has that stockpile there. He was gonna truck that off-site, but now we can just truck that to
over to the house proposed house site. So,
you know, in general, I didn't have a lot of time to work on the specifics of it this afternoon, but it looks like about a third less disturbance in the
regulated area
over on the westerly side of the property where the fills are gonna have to be taken out
and over
to the house prod site.
>> Okay, is this reflected
in an updated
work? Can this be reflected in an updated plan? Yeah,
>> I don't know. So
reduction in the area of disturbance is not
reflected in the updated plan, but everything else should be,
which should be, well, actually should be on a plan seven thirty.
I don't know what plan was submitted. I didn't submit the plans that are wetlands. The owners did, so that's a question I asked them.
Seven thirty is the plan. Okay.
>> So seven thirty, yeah. So you went from a three bedroom to a four bedroom septic, which basically added,
oh, let's see how many feet to the trenches. Added about 10 feet to the length of the the septic trenches and just increased the size of the tank by 250
gallons.
Still all within the same
area of disturbances before. We're not disturbing any more area than
we had proposed before
>> by doing that. Okay. So it'll just be a shallower
excavation.
>> Yeah. But not not necessarily shallower, just smaller in area.
Okay. Area,
maybe maybe slightly shallower
too.
Is it possible to queue up the newest
plan?
>> You should have the seven thirty plan. Yeah.
That looks
kinda small on my screen.
Let's see. Yeah.
That's it. That's the seven thirty plan right there.
Alright then. So
>> you can see the four bedroom septic.
We slid the house back 10 feet in one of the revisions,
but again, we didn't we didn't change the disturbed area of disturbance.
You know, still holding that same limited disturbance
in the back there.
We had considered using the existing pathway for the for the new driveway.
But when we looked at that, that was gonna cause more disturbance,
more driveway doing it that way. So we we stuck with the original plan coming in which showing on the plan. I know we had discussed that at one point,
but that just didn't seem like a good alternative.
Then there's been some stuff added which is a zoning issue with a lot line modification in the frontage and we show where the old the old road was there and things. That that's that's all to do with with zoning, not with, you know, not with wetlands.
Any questions or comments
from commissioners?
>> So George, I guess this is Jed.
From
our
minutes from the last meeting,
we were looking to get
the engineer to do a site plan review on the updated plan when received.
And so as far as I know we don't have that review yet.
>> Hold on a second here I'm trying to reconstruct
that
Okay.
So
the question then is whether this
plan data seven
thirty
has the required information with respect to
Upland Review area delineation.
Has that.
It was changed from 100 to 200.
Judge, does that satisfy your concern?
>> No, I was expecting a letter in our file under the application
from the Antique River
discussing the application and I see nothing there.
>> So I have one that I think I received back on July 19 from Brandon.
Ian Field from Yantic,
which I addressed the comments and
sent him revised plans last week, but have not gotten anything in writing back from just kind of got a verbal from him this afternoon.
The only thing really left
to determine is, you know, exactly how much fill are we gonna take out of the westerly side of the property. How much fill do we need to take out
to to make it an even cut and fill in the flood plain between there and the, the house site?
And like I said before, we had figured the the the fill we had figured the entire fill on the house site up to the elevation three twenty five five for the
slab elevation.
And but we determined today that that was too
didn't need to be done. It only needed to go up to three twenty three five.
So, basically, we're taking putting
the last two feet of fill on on the house site does not need to come out of the flood plain because that's being filled above the flood plain elevation.
Therefore, we're gonna be taking less fill out of the westerly side of the site.
Looks like probably about 200 yards, in neighborhood of 200 yards based on my
quick calculations I had time to do this afternoon before the meeting,
which will probably bring down the area of disturbance by about a third
from what's shown on that seven thirty plan.
>> Okay, so Jud, are you suggesting we
defer further consideration that we have that
documentation?
>> I think we have to.
Know, that was part
of the deal is
Megan wanted
the engineering review
and we discussed last time
that
should
be done once
the updated plan was received.
And I looked at this, you know,
I am certainly
inadequate
to make a
call on the appropriateness.
I guess my cut was not being a soil scientist, not being a civil engineer, any of those things,
that the amount of fill that we were going to take out to build up the site
was
a significant,
a more substantial,
I won't use the word significant because we said it wasn't,
activity
in a wetland upland review area.
I was counting on seeing what the engineer said about that after we got
the final approved plan to
help make the decision on that.
>> Well, that's kind of the discussion we had this afternoon. I mean, the engineer about how we can.
You know, make that impact as small as possible. And then we started talking about
we only need to fill. We actually need to take fill out of that area to get to the three twenty three five so.
We've actually decreased the amount we're taking out by about 200 yards.
Just with that.
In play now.
>> I expect that's a positive development,
but I think Jed has a good point there. We really do need the
plan that reflects that and the documentation, the engineering documentation
that was previously requested
before we can
proceed with the application.
>> I'm just looking that we have what we agreed at the last meeting we were going to have to make the decision.
>> So
again, in light of the need to move on with our
meeting,
Jed, I would entertain a motion to table further discussion
until we have this,
again the final revised plan and the documentation
requested
which
I would think should be available
for our next meeting. And I believe we are within the timeline
for
She
asked for the engineering timeline
for action on this.
>> Yes, George, this is Linda, you are. Maximum
action date is the August 5 and you have a ninety day extension by executive. Right,
>> okay. Yeah, I was scrolling down to that on the agenda. Thank you, Linda.
Okay,
so
as I said,
we really need a motion
here to
move on.
>> This is Jed, I'll make a motion that we table
the application on 57 Hendy Road
until we have the engineering review on the updated plan.
>> Excuse me. This is Bill Phillips. Can I say something?
Since you're the property owner, go ahead.
>> Yeah. My question is I'm reading through the minutes, and it said that
Megan Lawley asked for the engineer to do a split plan review
on the updated plan that we received. And our understanding was that was what she did what he did on this letter that was sent in
from him.
I'll open up to the screen. So I thought that's what what we provided.
Actually the town provided with hiring this engineer
to
do a study of this land
and that's what he did and gave all his recommendations
and then we provided that on our map.
So that's why I'm not clear what more you're asking for if he's already done this.
You know, we've provided everything
that we've been asked up to this point. So,
you know we thought we were gonna be able to get an approval tonight to
move towards getting this project underway.
We have all the information right here. Andrew spoke to the engineer today. I mean he had all this information
earlier this week
and didn't get back to Andrew. They spoke today
and we have the information. Andrew just explained it.
>> You know, as I said The issue here is that we don't have the documentation.
>> Is it possible to to move towards an approval with getting that exact yardage
that we could provide that exact yardage
with an approval.
What's the wording you would use? It would be no more than 600.
No no I know that. Yes
we could get in a condition with
an approval with conditions on the exact yardage because I think that's all we're looking at. We're just running out of time
for
my daughter to build a house.
You know, we've that's why we've been proactive on getting all our information in
and we're just running out of time.
Okay, well.
>> I think that's the only thing that we don't have is the amount of yardage and Andrew just explained that but we just don't have it written on the map.
>> If we could
Well, again, what we don't have,
again, as requested at the previous meeting,
the
site plan review on
the updated plan.
I'm not sure which,
okay.
We're
getting a little off topic here because we do have a motion here at the table.
And I want to get back to Jed on this.
It's ambiguous here.
You were referring to something from
Yantic, right?
Yes.
>> Okay.
And it just says the engineer in the minute, so it's not clear
>> She specifically said Brandon at the last meeting was the Who we're talking about. Yeah.
Yeah, I'm sorry, I didn't hear you.
Well,
>> the question was to
Commissioner Larson regarding
the specific information
that seems to be lacking
in
the application
as
we have it in hand.
Again,
the plan
for 07/30 has
not been updated to
the current
proposal of removing less
cut from the west
side of the property
to use as fill
for the structure
and then again the key question is about the
letter.
>> Well the reason I was speeding up about that
was because I'll be the I'm the site contractor that will be doing the site work on this project.
That we if we go forward with this.
So I would be doing all the site work.
I'm the owner of Landy Construction.
We're a site work contractor.
And as far as my understanding was, correct me if I'm wrong, is the letter that we have from
Brandon
Anfield
has addressed all the conditions
and maybe Andrew can give me a little help on this
and that he's got them all on the map except for the concern today that about lowering the impact with the fill.
Can you shed any more light on that Andrew? Right. I think that's correct correct statement.
>> You know, I I submitted everything that he wanted, information and the changes to the plans he wanted in that in that memo
except for the fill quantities are gonna you know gonna change.
>> Okay I'm a little confused here because I'm not seeing that in our
in our documents
you know, in the documentation
for
this application.
Could you give me a specific title for that?
Linda, can you help me out with this?
This is the letter from
Hanfield.
>> It would have been in the meeting packet from the last meeting is where you'd find it.
>> It was never posted. I think George, what you're looking for is Brandon's
review
of the
updated site plans that was done on 07/30.
Is that what you're looking for?
>> It's a letter dated June 25. Yeah. It's dated June 25.
>> I'm holding it up as I'm speaking. There's been no significant change to the plan. Well, it's it's been totally illogical. Change to the plan.
>> It was sent to us by Josephine. But, George, if if you are looking for another review from Brandon from Yantic River Consultants.
>> Okay, I have a packet here. I'm also looking on the web. Right, there's nothing
past the June 25.
>> Okay, in our current
applications
list, we have application site plan May 18, the MUDRS list, statewide IWC
activity reporting form,
project description,
Addendum B, proposed erosion and sedimentation controls, Phoenix Lab Report,
review by Hank Gruner, site plan
revised seventhirtytwenty.
>> IWWC
chair was copied.
It was from Joseph Wagner. Joseph Wagner sent this to
Wetlands.
Joseph Wagner sent it to the Right, this is the cover. Yeah, they have it. Right. I think Yeah. This is what this is where they sent this letter to us.
Joseph
Wagner
sent
random letter to us
on July 27. Mhmm. Okay. That should be part of
their packet. If it wasn't uploaded,
it should have been.
Andrew, do you have that letter also?
Yeah.
Schumhouse, what what letter are we talking about now?
>> So letter from from Brandon Hanfield, the first letter that was submitted back before the last meeting.
>> Okay. It was submitted the day of the meeting.
Yeah. We didn't have time to respond to it because it was submitted the day of the meeting or the last meeting. We didn't get it till during the meeting. We got it during the meeting. Yeah.
>> I'm looking at all the materials that I have both from the previous meeting and
posted on the applications
under applications
under application 2023
on our
town website
and I'm simply not seeing that
unless it's in the P and Z supporting documents.
>> George?
This is Joe Joe Wagner. I was I
I emailed you that letter. Megan emailed it to you, but I think she used
incorrect email address.
So I I emailed it. It was probably,
like, an hour or two before the meeting
>> because I noticed the email address was wrong. Hold on a second. Let me let me check my email then.
Okay.
The only, I
have two messages from Wetlands here, Joe. One includes
the
site
documents, the site plan for 12 Webster Lane.
And the next one,
the other one here is
pertains to an enforcement action
at Route 87.
So no, I did not receive
the
document you just mentioned.
And again, if it's not on our website, if it's not,
Jed, do you have this letter? I mean, I I do not have it. Okay.
>> Got it from Joe. Jim?
Nope. They showed it at the last meeting.
>> Yeah. We got it during the meeting, last
lands meeting from Joe Wagner.
No. We got it on the twenty seventh. On the twenty seventh? Yeah. On the July
27.
>> But the the letter was presented at the last meeting by Megan Le It was shown on the screen. Shown on the screen
>> at the last meeting. It was shown on the screen the last meeting
because that's when
We did. Yeah. We got it at the meeting. Shot of it.
Can forward it to someone that
>> Yeah.
That's all very well, but it
doesn't really give us time
to receive it or consider it.
And
we do have a motion on the floor
but we have a motion without a second
to table the discussion
so I'm going to hold this discussion until we resolve that
question. Jed, do you want to continue your motion? Do want to
look for a second to that motion
to table?
I think we should continue with the motion.
>> We just wanted to get to the bottom of the confusion because we're a little confused at this point. We are too and as I say we're going
>> I'm going to have to cut you off here because we really do need to move on this.
And I think the best thing really is the table of motion and to try and get this resolved
ex parte not within the context of trying to conduct a meeting on Zoom.
This is not a very efficient way to No,
move things
>> we agree. It's more difficult trying to do this on Zoom.
>> So
getting back to the meeting
per se, we have,
Jed, you made a motion, correct? Yes.
Okay.
Then I'll ask if there's a second
to that motion.
Because remember, if there's no second, then the motion disappears. Second to motion, Jim Helles.
Okay, Jim, thank you. So we've got a motion by Jed, seconded by Jed Larson,
second by
Jim Halsey to
table further discussion until we have in hand
the documentation
that we requested
the
updated information
reflected
in tonight's discussion.
So with a motion and a second, I'll go through a roll call vote.
Commissioner Larson?
Aye.
Commissioner Halsey?
Commissioner Smith?
Aye.
Okay and
Vice Chairman Elliott
also votes aye so the motion to table
carries
four-zero-zero.
We will take this up at our next meeting or a special meeting if necessary
as soon as we receive
again the information
and that's posted
in our
applications folders
on the website and all the commissioners
have access to it.
Moving on then we have
our next item on the agenda
Permit Application
IWWC
twenty-twenty
five.
Jeff Palemas of Skips Water on
behalf of the owners at 157
Lake Ide Drive for a septic installation in Upland Review area.
Okay,
could Skip be unmuted?
Jeff Polinus be unmuted.
Hear me.
>> Are
there any updates on this
or further discussion
on this application?
>> I just want to know if the commission members can hear me speaking.
>> We can hear you now. Okay.
All of sudden something happened and you came through loud and clear.
At
>> our last or at your last meeting on July 14, we presented our plan for the repair
or replacement of the septic system
for John and Jen Benda
at 157
Lakeside Drive. There were
no requests for revisions to the plan and, no additional information
was requested or submitted
on behalf of this application.
We were just here
tonight hoping that if there's any other questions from the commission members, be happy to address those
or hoping for
an approval so that we can move forward with
>> this plan that has already been approved by the Thad King with Eastern Highlands Health District
and
move forward with the repair
in the next coming weeks
on their property. So their
septic system will be updated and ready to function for them.
>> Okay,
thank you. Any
questions or comments from any of the commissioners?
Okay, hearing and seeing
no alerts.
I'll ask for a motion
on this permit application.
I think a motion to approve would be in order.
I'd like to move to approve the
application of John and
Jan Benda.
Do we have a second for that motion?
Jen seconds.
>> Okay so a motion by Jim Jim Halsey second by Jed Larson to approve the permit application
any
further discussion are there any conditions that we want to make sure
are included or any other
items pertinent to that application?
Okay.
>> I believe the standard conditions from our
summary ruling,
correct me if I'm wrong, but anybody,
but I mean they
spell out
issues like bill fence will be in place,
construction,
you know,
perhaps be infected,
things of that nature, pretty simple.
That are standard conditions that are part of that summary ruling that goes out.
>> That would be my understanding.
Any comments
from our
agent,
mister Wagner?
>> I was just trying to look to see
if it was there there would be a best management practices.
So I would agree with Jim, but I'm not sure like where specifically they are listed.
>> Believe in our summary ruling form.
I
didn't realize they were there until recently.
>> Joey had just done a septic tank
upgrade
on
probably
Lake Road Range.
Lynn,
I forget her last name, but she just put in a new septic tank that should have had all the standard approvals
on that you might use for a model.
>> So
could we put a condition in for, utilizing best management practices?
>> Yeah. I think and we could defer to
agent Wagner on on what conditions are imposed.
I'm referring again back to best,
Joe's referring to his best management practice.
And I think they're pretty much on the plan, as I recall.
Don't think asking for anything that wasn't
proposed.
>> This is Linda for the commission.
As part of the standard form for the summary ruling,
it does state in the first paragraph that you're approving it because all feasible
measures have been met.
So,
written into the summary ruling in the first paragraph, and it's part of the approval.
I'm just trying to pull one up now.
It says can you guys still hear me? Yes, can. Yep. It says,
I move that the application as described below be approved and a permit be granted with the conditions listed
below because all prudent and feasible measures have been taken to minimize the impact on the wetlands and no feasible and prudent alternative
exists.
That's part of the language in the summary ruling, and then there's the standard conditions that follow.
And there are E and S controls, things of that nature. Yeah, let scroll down for a second. Let me see what I've got here.
The standard conditions
say the permit's
valid for two years from date of approval,
that the applicant has to get additional permits if required.
Let's see.
Yes, All activities for the prevention of soil erosion, including but not limited to, silt fences and hay bales shall be conducted under the direct supervision
of a certified engineer who shall employ the best management practices, etcetera, etcetera.
Thank you, Lynette.
>> So we can take those, standard conditions as read,
as part of this motion then
to include?
>> Yeah, you can phrase the motion that
state all standard conditions apply,
along that matter. I
>> will add that to the
action.
Move
to approve the application
conditions.
Okay, Jed, is that acceptable for your second?
Yes. Okay.
>> So any further discussion then?
If not, then I will ask for a roll call vote on the motion.
Jim Halsey?
Aye.
Ted Larson?
Ed Smith?
Aye.
And George Eliot also aye. The motion carries four-zero-zero.
You got your permit.
You know what to do.
Okay.
Well,
moving on.
We're at
agenda item eight,
violations and enforcement actions.
So we'll turn it over to Mr. Wagner. The first up
for
complaint
re violation of permit conditions,
including unauthorized
development
in an upland review area and floodplain,
a gravel driveway parking area, and failure to install and maintain proper erosion and sediment controls
at 27
Hendi Road,
Hector Rivera,
responsible.
So,
that's new and we don't have any documentation
on that as yet so
>> yeah I haven't I haven't,
gotten any new information on that actually
time I saw it was on
the agenda,
so I definitely have to look into that.
>> Okay.
So then
I guess there's nothing we can do about that.
>> Sure, this is Jim Howison. Yeah, Jim. I
was told at the last meeting that a commissioner cannot discuss
enforcement actions.
I'm not sure why.
So I'm not gonna add anything to Joe's
comments.
>> Okay.
But we will certainly want to visit this at our next meeting and get the information
pertaining to this complaint
and our options
as a commission,
with respect to any actions
that may be required.
>> Yeah. I'll,
I'll collect all the information and
try and contact them.
I'll provide a report next month.
>> All right.
Okay.
How about item number b,
the cessation
disorder,
for activities at 129 Hebron Road.
>> That one, I talked to Ruby
a couple times.
She told me they're working with a engineer
to
resubmit a new permit,
with the engineer's help.
They're trying to get it in for this meeting, but I didn't see anything. And
they plan to put all their proposed activities
that they're gonna do on the site, under one permit,
including the activities listed under the cease and desist order.
They also plan to submit drawings
for a new fence in the wetland area
that uses a
different type of, footing spaced apart,
not a trench,
and a solid footing like the fence in the front of the yard. But
they were
adding that to the site plan, and
I take it they didn't they didn't get it all done in time for this meeting.
>> Well, there's clearly no application
on the agenda and I didn't see any new information
pertinent to that application.
>> On I
the
would expect to see something
for the next month
>> just talking to them. And have you seen any activity at the site or have you been to the Yeah,
I haven't been to the site yet. Okay.
>> Next.
And here's where I think I just did get some information.
The
order read me a deposition of material
at forty one and
thirty three Route eighty seven
on the construction and open review. Can you
update on that?
>> Yeah.
Megan received a letter from an attorney representing the Nichols.
Attorney said the Nichols were still waiting for mister Bohm to provide a contractor's license and a proof of insurance
before they allowed him to start their remediation
work on their property.
They sent the letter to, the the letter from their attorney to Mark Brandt.
He said the commission could hold an advisory vote,
an informal vote to decide whether they want me, the agent, to commence legal action through the supreme court.
But that's what I have on that.
I was told that there
is proof of insurance,
but I'm not sure.
I I guess they were we're kinda waiting for
missus Nichols and mister Bohm to come to an agreement so that mister Bohm can
go on their property and and
remove the material.
>> Okay,
this would be the letter
from
Robert m Elliot PC.
>> Yes. I think Megan tried to send it to you earlier, but she sent it to the wrong address.
Okay. Some reason on here.
Yes. So you should have got it earlier, but I I just noticed that your address was
had a misspelling in it,
this evening. So
>> Okay. Well, I've got it. Yeah. I just pulled that up now.
Okay.
Part of it obviously relates
to
Nickel's insistence
on
insurance
affidavit, so forth.
But there are also I see a claim here
by the attorney
that
Mr. Baum has continued to the last sentence of that letter
Mr. Baum has continued to clear and add debris to the pile within other parts of the designated wetland areas,
which clearing is showing Mr. Bowne's
disdain,
incorrect usage
there,
should be disdain,
and disobedience
of the Inland Wetland Commission orders.
So
obviously we haven't
had any recent updates on this activity.
So have you, Joe, been able to
visit the property or do you have any
>> personal No,
have not visited the property. What I'm probably gonna have to go there with Jim because I really don't have any
Other than a few photos on the website,
I don't
have any contacts. Like, I I'm not sure what it looked like originally.
So I think it would be best if if I paid a visit with Jim just to see
what the difference was.
In terms of of activity since the So we can so we can, yeah, figure out if he was making if he was adding materials
or or not.
>> All right,
okay because this obviously
has been dragging on for quite some time
without any
progress
it seems
and there are a lot of moving parts, including
the
shed
that was placed on illegally deposited fill
and so on.
And
if there's further
activity
in contravention of the commission's
ruling,
that would be a
disturbing development that would require, I think, some further action on our part.
So
Jim, can you
arrange to
assist
Joe with
getting on Okay, what's going on
because again, do
I'd certainly like to see something happen
in terms of remediating
that.
And between the
adjoining Landovers being loggerheads
and the
potential for further activity,
Again, it seems that some action is on the commission's part and on the Welland's agent's part required to get up to speed on this,
figure out what's going on.
So I guess we'll have to leave it at that for now
and
again
revisit that at our next meeting.
Is there any time for public comment or no?
>> We
don't have public comment on the agenda further,
but since you're the abutting landowner, I think this would be
I'm just very
>> Okay. I'm just very concerned because we've been doing this since February. We have all our documentation. We have a number of pictures and everything.
And we just keep it push, push. And now he has filled further down,
made a new pathway further down. So obviously,
the dumping in the inland wetland doesn't mean anything to him because there truly hasn't been any action taken against him if he's still doing this. And I'm just concerned because
of the floodwaters that do happen because of the brook in the elevation
of my yard. So
I have a finished And
with the water, I'm just very concerned.
At some point, I mean, we keep continuing,
continuing, different commission, this and that. But
that's why we had the lawyer draft the letter looking for a time frame. Yes,
>> understand your concern.
And again,
we're trying to address this in a
difficult situation,
both with respect to
our ability to meet and the fact that we have not had
your
request came in at a very awkward time
with respect to
the commission's enforcement arm, namely we had a retirement
and
a short term and
then an interim
Welland's agent I'm hopeful that Mr. Wagner will be able to
move the ball on this we are not
you know procrastinating
on this we just haven't been able to move
>> Okay, but again,
every meeting there's
something different. And I understand,
I completely get this, and I appreciate the volunteers
in that. But every meeting,
there's another issue that's preventing this from happening
yet again. And I'm just looking for a time frame and where do I get a copy of this recorded meeting as well.
>> Ed Smith speaking.
Perhaps it's time for us to have another sidewalk, all of us, because
>> Jed, I, I think Jim, you were there, right? We can look at that together
>> instead That's of just one of
certainly a possibility, yes. Okay.
>> Maybe we can expedite it by having a
special session.
>> And
I think that what we can
assure is that
at the next meeting
we will have a resolution on this. There will be,
again, opportunity for site well, for
our wetlands agent,
at least Mr. Hallisey and Mr. Smith,
to
take a look and
see if, again, it was particularly with respect to
any
further activity
in the wetland.
And
can't
off the top of my head give you a timeline,
but we can construct that in terms of the legal requirements
for
moving,
if we need to, to move to
our next step of action. We're currently
in an
order to remediate,
and
further
action,
further legal action
would have
an inherent
timeline.
>> So the order to remediate that was in February there was no there's no timeline for that is that what you're saying
>> I don't have that I you'll have to give me a minute to to see what that order said I don't have that
in front of me
>> it was a certified letter issued in February
with a
timeline and fines
>> You'll have to give me a moment to look on that.
Okay, we
have an order to remediate,
which is dated,
again,
February 24.
And I don't have any okay we have a the letter
issued
by our former enforcement
officer
And
no, I do not see a timeline other than the
putative show cause hearing.
But there's no timeline
in
the
order to remediate.
>> So then I guess my question is what is the purpose of an order to remediate
if there's no timeline to fix it? Because I've turned in everything that was asked of me. We're still waiting. And
there's just
now you're moving to the end of September,
and there's still no resolution then.
I regret I cannot
address that question.
>> Where do I go from here? Who else can I talk to? Because in my opinion,
the commission is not doing the job that they were
they were commissioned
to do.
>> Well,
we would have, the town
would have to
start an enforcement
action.
We would have to seek damages
and
we would have to work with our attorney.
May come to that if we don't get any actions.
And as I say, I want to hear from our well known agent
before we proceed and I want to investigate
this claim
of further
disturbance
and
further activity
in the wetlands.
>> Okay, but
that's
something new from what was before. So again,
where do I get a copy of this recorded meeting? And then where do I get the information for
your attorney for the town so I can follow-up?
>> I don't think well, can get a copy of the
minutes of the meeting.
Linda, what's the deal on
the recorded
meeting?
>> The audio should be up on the website probably tomorrow.
Okay.
>> Thank you.
And then the name of the attorney, is that on the website? Or
>> should I just send a name? I don't think you would be authorized to speak to the town attorney in this room. Okay. So how
>> do we get a message that I would like that conversation to happen?
>> I believe that that is beyond the scope of our discussion at the moment.
Okay. And can that be reflected in the minutes?
That statement is recorded, yes.
Thank you.
>> Again, I understand that you're
frustrated and concerned
at the
speed or the slowness, I should say,
of developments in this situation,
but I don't think that we're in any position to make any warranties
about
progress,
except to say that we are
going to
investigate
the situation.
And
now that we have Eleven's agent again,
to try and move
the
owner,
Mr. Boehm, to take action
on this remediation.
And that
the commission will
seek to enforce
that order.
Thank you.
>> Okay, moving on we have a couple of other pending
or continuing
items
in the enforcement.
One would be
number E,
the
complaint regarding
activity on Townsend Road,
permitting Matthew Hagerty.
Any update on that?
>> I went I drove by there this morning.
There's no culverts yet.
There's still temporary bridge for the equipment, so two
planks going across the wetland.
The wetland was dry from what I could see. There was no standing water in it.
Rather.
>> There were hay bales
along the entrance and exits of the temporary bridge.
I also observed two shipping containers
and
some smaller construction or implements near the containers.
The containers were in between the wetland and the road.
I'm
not sure if that's the way it was before,
but that's how it is as of this morning.
>> Right.
I
don't have the
record in front of me, but I believe that we,
had asked for
action
regarding erosion control, that would be the hay bales.
Jim, can I tap your memory for
what the
commission requested
about
that situation?
>> When I was brought in, I'm gonna be careful because I was again,
I understand that, yeah.
>> I was asked to follow-up on the complaint when Josh had left.
Right. And
>> hay bales were installed.
And at that time,
didn't realize it, it initially became apparent that
basically he got an approval to build a house on that lot,
and he installed
a temporary crossing
as a logging operation,
which is, he's a logger by trade,
he hasn't
put the driveway in. I mean, fill for the driveway hasn't
been installed. I mean, fact, culverts will go in at that time, I'm sure.
So it's an ongoing project.
We believe
Ragerty is now
moving on it,
now to build the house at this time.
So
the complaint
was essentially addressed,
but now there's,
Joe had pointed out, there's
material, I'd say material, shipping containers.
There were logs there.
And I did speak to him
about moving the logs, so he agreed to do that.
So it's fluid
situation.
He addressed
the outstanding plate and now it's sort of a follow-up.
One thing that I did learn from that is
take a look at that constructed
sequence.
Never really paid that much attention to it until this realized the importance of it.
And I don't think applicants
do either.
I mean, was no temporary crossing on that plan.
So it kind of it's kind of hard to monitor I'm
just pointing it out so that
>> That's a point very well taken that we had we
approved a permit
for
you know that the application was for a driveway and
you know we did a sidewalk and we looked at it and said okay you can put a driveway through here with according to the engineering plan
and then we got the complaint about logging
and
the assurance we got at that time was that in fact it wasn't well it was logging but it was lot clearing
for construction which obviously makes sense. But then again
we have a
temporary
driveway
and
construction activities
going on
and it's hard to match that up
with
the permit that we issued.
>> I think in this case it needs be resolved.
I mean,
not gonna blow up in my opinion.
I mean, we move forward,
it will resolve itself. I just
pointing it out because
easy, easy,
when I look at,
when I used to look at construction sequence, it didn't mean that much to me. And after experiencing
that,
I'm going to pay a little more attention
to that portion of the plan,
I guess.
>> Good point.
Okay, so
do we need to continue
to
monitor
this
and keep it on our agenda for future meetings?
George, this is Hank. Can you hear me? Yeah. Can I weigh in on this as I
>> had visited the site with Jim at the request of Megan?
You may remember when
the complaint was made because I had raised the concern about the possibility of doing more damage by removal of the trees that were felled in the wetland versus just leaving them in at that point.
Even the seasonality.
But one thing and, you know, I wanted to point out is when I when I visited the site.
You know, the concern about the temporary
driveway that's there,
my concern is about hydrological connectivity
there.
And I'm a little concerned, you know, it's one thing to have the approvals where there's the culverts that would allow the flow through there,
but absent that it's it's you know, a very temporary situation and I'm a little concerned that
given the timing this is this project is kind of bleeding down the road,
that there may be alterations to the hydrology of that wetland because that's the the sourcing is coming down off of that that drainage pathway there that's been bisected by
the temporary
driveway.
I don't have any sense of when he may be going to complete that project, you know, install the culverts and
get back to that.
Anybody have any sense of the timing on this now?
>> Well, would have to contact the well oiled agent to do that because supervision
of construction is part of the permit. And
clearly, he has not done that.
So yeah, it's all in advance.
And you're right, there is a concern then about
God willing and the creek does rise,
we will have rain and there will be runoff and it's not going to go the way it would have
prior to this disturbance.
>> Yeah,
Jim Halsey,
things one. He recently pulled a building permit and my understanding is that that development,
building on that site is imminent.
Any,
the crossing,
I appreciate
Hank's concern,
certainly,
and it kind of, I was a little surprised that I hadn't,
I didn't realize what was going on there, but it is a, it's a corduroy road,
so I believe water is traveling
underneath it.
I mean it's,
crossing is, it's a logging,
it's a logging crossing.
>> Yeah,
I've seen quite a lot of variability on logging crossings and wetlands however, so I guess my suggestion would be that that would be you know worth the monitoring, you know, to sort of just watch that, you know, given that this is seeming to take a longer time for it to get to
actual build out.
You know, that was just that's just my recommendation.
Thanks. And I certainly didn't mean to downplay your concern. Bill, get me wrong. No, no, I didn't I didn't take it as a downplay, but I just I'm just concerned because I don't think any of us sort of
realized that at the beginning.
And that was a bit of a surprise to me when I went out when we were looking at
felled trees,
you know, which were,
you know, I think quite frankly less of a concern than hydrological impacts to the wetlands in my view.
>> Should we not ask him to come before us and tell us why he didn't put it in the driveway like we told him to with the culvert
before he starts doing any building back there?
>> I
just think it's worth monitoring.
I'm not sure, you know, it would be worth getting a better sense of the timetable on it. But
I think it's just worth monitoring to make sure that that's,
you know, the, it's not altering the flow pattern through there. And I think it will require
during installation,
it will require a little bit of oversight just to make sure that that's handled in the you know the best possible way to ensure that
hydrology
and also hopefully that there's a reduction in potential spread of invasives into the wetland through that disturbance there.
>> Yeah, because I think the Wetlands Commission's
expectation was the first thing he was going to do is put a culvert in there and put the driveway over it.
>> That's,
I believe I was on the commission when that was approved and that's certainly my recollection as well.
>> Yeah, we had no discussion about putting a temporary
bridge across there.
>> Yeah,
I think it's more it's almost like you know, it's two different projects like there's this forestry operation.
And then there's
residential construction driveway thing. I think it's, you know, it's being it's kind of like one of those mixes.
>> Well, I agree with Jim's comment. We got to pay more attention to that sequence of construction and just,
you know, once we approve it, we've got to keep going out there and watch it to make sure they're doing what they tell us they're going to do.
>> Yeah, I think the site prep
piece is really important.
Yep.
Anyway, I'll shut up for now. That was my recommendation. Would just suggest Thank you. You. Okay.
>> So
we may need some enforcement action here.
And
I
guess pending further activity,
I think it would be
reasonable to
ask Mr. Hagerty about
his present plans and when is he going to actually do that driveway
because
he didn't get a permit to do a corridor road.
He didn't get a, you know, he didn't get a permit to do that kind of fill activity
in the wetland.
>> Yeah. I can I
can contact him and
see what what his timeline is
for that?
>> Okay.
I think stress the need to get
things in order
as soon as possible.
Yeah.
>> Okay,
moving on then,
the
last enforcement action
at 28 Shawty Mill Road, Matthew Grant,
disturbance
to a well.
Seems to me that that was
nearly resolved
previously,
but
it's on the agenda.
>> Can I, defer to Jim on that one?
Is that, permissible?
>> I asked him to stop and he stopped.
That's what I thought. And I wanted to follow-up and give him some guidance on what he can do.
He's really talking about
crops. Crops is the term he used, so sort of
gardening or whatever.
But he, he,
yeah, he was easy to deal with.
Sort of follow-up with sort of some information with him. I can go through Joe on it.
Okay. There we go.
>> Yeah. I can
can do that. I'll get
with him and
come up with some recommendation.
>> Okay, that takes care of everything on the agenda for item number eight. Moving to item number nine,
agent report,
permit monitoring
activity for
the town connectivity project,
and
the
gravel
extraction
on Route
6.
>> Yeah, both of those,
I don't have much information on. Not enough to learn. I
spoke with Megan about the gravel operation
during my interview,
but I other than that, that's really all I know about it, but there is one.
The town connectivity project, basically the same. I just I I need more information before I can report on anything.
>> Has there been any activity
that you're aware of
with any of those?
>> That I've been informed of
or made aware of. No. Okay.
>> George, can I can I jump in on the gravel operation because I was involved
in that?
I monitor that you know they put in John Valente when John was still there. Yeah, I had worked with the with the applicant on the installation of the erosion control which was also as you may remember serving as exclusion pension for the woods. Right.
I monitor that pretty heavily right through the spring and through the wood turtle nesting season into the
first week of July.
And it took a bit of effort to, you know, there were probably three times when it needed repairs. It took some nudging for them to go out and, you know, fix some areas where the the
fencing had been plowed under by
some some activity on the roadway there and
by some fallen trees, things like that. But they did it, they maintained it and it certainly worked up to
its exclusionary
role with the turtles. I was able to monitor six turtles there that were using the area, none of them moved into the project area,
and one was kind of following right along the fence line, so it worked very carefully.
But I have not been monitoring it since the turtles, now we're in the inactive season where they're out in the floodplain, but I would recommend to the
to
Joe to, you know, periodically go out there and check it because, know, they were somewhat lax on
on maintaining
the
Rosen control fencing there. It
didn't seem to be that big of an issue because of the sandy soils there from what I saw with the rainstorms that we had as far as You
know any any flow issues. It was more issues associated with
work activities that were knocking it down, but it would be worth continuing to monitor.
The other thing that I think is we would need to get a handle on a little bit is the timetable of that project has now been you know, fairly well delayed while there's activity out there.
Matthew Another
key element will be restoration removal of the fencing and restoration.
There was a vertical pull back there that they were Doctor. Avoiding which they were, but there were some restoration needs that were part of the conditions. And I wanted to get a better sense of the timing of when that might occur. So I've asked, you know, it might be a good recommendation for Joe to follow-up with the project manager and try to get a sense of when they may be completing that project from entering
the restoration phase.
>> Yeah, I can I
can contact them and see
what they have for a timeline?
>> And I'd be happy, Joe, if you want to, you know, to go out there with you.
And I can introduce you to the folks over at the,
the auto parts store that are sort of the owners there. They're the ones that I've dealt with mostly there because the prop, you know, I haven't really seen the project manager much.
You know, I'd be happy to happy to do that if you'd like. Yeah. That'd be good.
>> Yeah. This is Jim Halsey. I do monitored as well as
zoning agent, and
I concur. There's
been a few times where there's been issues that the owners have taken care of it. I do want to point out though that if you're going to refer to the roof gravel operation, you're going to need to put the address on it,
because it will be corrected.
I
don't know the address, but
it would behoove you to plug in the street number.
>> Yeah, it's listed on the agenda is simply Map 33 Block 36 Lot 23.
>> I wasn't impressed on the plan if I remember right.
>> The reason I bring it up is it's always at the planning and zoning commission meeting when I report on it,
it always comes up
and when the minutes are
reviewed, it comes up.
I
thought it was gonna approach this proactively.
Mhmm.
>> I I can get, I can get Linda the address. It's not a problem.
>> Again, it's not given an address. It's simply referred to immediately West of
Route 6.
Is Linda. I could not find an actual street address for it. It may not have a street address. It may just be a lot.
>> I think we refer to it as the the gravel operation next to the extra mile.
Which
>> does have an address. I didn't mean to make a big deal about it. I'm sorry. Okay.
>> Well, then,
okay, we'll take that as read. It's gonna be reviewed. You're gonna get the timeline
on
their
current.
I mean, of course,
when they made the proposal, they were wanting to get the gravel and sand out as soon as possible
anticipating
construction and then, well, everything hit the fan. And so they're probably backed up and not moving much material
but nevertheless trying to find out when they're planning to do because if it does bleed into another
season
of vernal activity,
we particularly want to be sure that the
silt and barrier fencing is in good order.
And of course, Hank can
advise you on that, Joe. Yeah, okay.
Okay, now the other item here is the we brought
up last time about trying to expedite
the
work permits or
basically permitting for town activities, things like the
drainage at Shawty Mill.
And
I think you were charged with finding out about other
towns in the area and how they handle
there is, as it were, internal
permit requirements.
>> Yeah. I haven't I
haven't found
one. I I mean, it looks like a lot of them use
an administrative
agent approval
for their projects. I haven't found one yet that has, like, a separate municipal permit form or something like that.
Some of them have different forms, like different permits
for minimal impact.
And a lot of those
road projects, if it's, like, maintaining existing
you know, and and it's not in a wetland, then it would fall under that.
And then it goes through the agent approval. That's what I found so far, but I'll keep looking and
>> Okay. Yeah. Well, I
guess in that case, what we'd have to do is to discuss
as a matter of board policy
what
level should
agent approval be
implemented and what level should the agent kick it off to the commission?
>> What I was going to try to do is look at enough of them to get a feel for what
the good
processes are and then maybe make a summary that I can present
Yeah, to the
>> and I think the differentiation, I mean, our permitting doesn't
differentiate
with level of activity.
But I think that might give us a clue
in terms of
what we would expect
you as the when you're authorized to to act as an agent.
Yeah.
>> Think that's basically what those
minimal permits were. They kinda clarify that, like, when when the agent can
you know, for the citizens and for the commission, like, what what falls under
the, you know, things that can be approved by an agent.
>> So Okay. This this is Jim Halas. You know, have a comment. I
can appreciate
what
we've
Megan and perhaps Eric were trying to do
sort of streamline the process for towns. And I understand that. I think along
with that has to be some sort of
follow-up with either
education on the part of
the crew
and or
keep it, you know, oversight.
Wetlands are not the Public Works Department's
priority. Don't think
if
they move us to
keep an eye on what goes that's all.
>> There's still yeah. Municipal
governments are still
considered to be under I I don't think there's any exemptions that that anything can fall under. It they still have they still have to go through the permitting process.
>> Yeah. I I was thinking more of the actual construction process. Mhmm. Sometimes
there's not a lot of oversight there.
>> Keeping
the crew on their toes
is what's really required here.
Yeah.
>> Not so much a matter of
how the permit is granted,
but making sure that the conditions of the permit
are adhered to Part of the process. Yeah.
Okay, well, we'll continue this discussion at
subsequent meetings.
Right now, think we can move to item number 10, other business.
I don't have any information on the
applications
for
three vacant well, we've got two vacant
alternate
positions
and
we
have evidently three applications and remember
I don't know who received those applications
or in any way they can be sure Jim you brought up a good point last time about making sure that they that the applicants are
registered
voters or I guess property owners who could be electors of the town.
>> Couldn't resist putting
that out. Yeah. And apparently they weren't, neither of the women were
registered voters.
Okay.
>> Which isn't a big deal. I mean, I think they're, they can be,
>> were gonna register to vote pretty quickly in Cincinnati. Yes, yes, it's not a, there's
>> no waiting for periods like getting a gun. Yeah, right. So I think that will resolve itself very quickly.
>> Okay,
and what about the third LP? Wendy, do you have anything on these?
>> As I say, I have no idea. I do. Actually, Megan sent a letter, maybe
notes for this meeting tonight.
And she said that
she confirms
that neither of the female applicants have been registered, but Gabriel Anderson has registered.
Megan
plans to prepare a recommendation to the Board of Selectmen when she gets back from vacation for her appointment.
Okay.
>> And she says she has not heard back from Elizabeth Miano as to whether or not she wishes to register.
Okay. And then she says
regarding the third application from William Monroe,
she's going to confirm with the registrar whether he is registered in town.
And she said, if he is, the commission may wish to interview him and recommend him in lieu of Ms. Miano at this time.
Okay.
>> And then she says,
Alternatively,
Wayne has expressed interest in stepping down. If he does so, or if Elizabeth chooses
not to register to vote, this would open up a third alternate position for Mr. Monroe or another individual to fill.
>> Okay,
okay.
Well, I think that's sufficient update and obviously there's no further action we can take tonight,
but we'll certainly hope to have
viable
applications
from all of these and
approval from the Board of Selectmen
so that we can have a fully constituted
commission.
Next item on the agenda and other business, our 2020 bylaws review.
The
bylaws,
I'll remind you, were revised
in 2019.
I looked back I don't have actually
an approved copy. I've got annotated copies of the bylaws,
but it seems that we approved them at our
May
meeting.
And so the question then is, is anybody on the commission
aware of any need to revise
our bylaws?
>> George, I think Megan sent out a
updated
copy of the bylaws, and I don't have them in front of me here.
>> I looked in my records They're pretty good.
I
think we did complete
our bylaws. It's just that as I say, I don't have anything that I would regard as a final copy
with the date of approval on it. It may been
sent out. I'm just saying that, you know, in terms of my
the folder that I have that says IWWC
Bylaws
does not contain
a final draft. Contains
what I believe is a draft that we approved
but it doesn't you
know it still has a markup
and all that in it
so
we can resolve that otherwise that's really not germane to the discussion here
again the question is do we have any need
to revise our bylaws
from
the most recent
revision.
>> I had a couple of concerns. Don't know if this is appropriate to bring it up.
>> Well, if it has to do with the bylaws, it's certainly appropriate. Okay. One of them actually goes back to
>> the filling of positions on the commission.
My recollection of the
the charter is that commissions fill their own
slots
for up to sixty five days or some period of time,
after which time the board of selectmen can can
may.
Meaning, I don't know why we're not,
as commission, we're not filling them.
But I may have that wrong.
>> We are actually, again, you're
right, Jim, that the
commission has the right to fill its own if a vacancy occurs,
what I believe would be called a casual vacancy when it's not as a result of
end of term.
So if casual vacancy occurs, then we do have the opportunity I think we've deferred
to the Board of Selectmen and sent them our recommendations
for filling that
just to make sure that everybody's on the same page.
But in effect,
are by our recommendation
to the Board of Selectmen,
I think we are in effect
filling the vacancy.
>> Okay, the what
I read was that Megan was going to
send these names on for
approval.
I just, I don't know, raise the question as to why we're not,
why the commission's not doing it on their own.
That is a good question.
>> Do wanna hear my other concerns? Sure.
People always address
resignations
and
letters have to go. Sometimes they don't.
Sometimes people
move out of town and don't don't resign.
I wish there was a way to address that. In fact,
it seems to have happened with the chairman of our CBA
>> very recently. Okay. So what do you call a de facto resignation?
Basically,
if a person moves out of town, then they're no longer eligible to serve.
Right. So
it's
not so much a
resignation as a disqualification.
And you're right, how do we address that
and
move on then to a point
a new
well to fill the vacancy.
>> I thought there was something in the bylaws that said if
a
member misses three meetings in a row other than for illness,
that is grounds for
>> dismissal or something. Yeah, but that's dismissal,
Jud, not as I say in the case that Jim brought up. First of all, we don't want to have to wait
on team meetings
when somebody's moved out of town
and is therefore no longer eligible to serve.
There ought to be a way to
handle that kind of vacancy.
I think the
situation of negligence
of not
fulfilling the obligations of being
a member of the Commission
is,
you know, that is an orderly process and
requires the waiting.
But
in the case of you know somebody becoming
ineligible
to serve on the commission we ought to be able to
act on that immediately.
That makes sense.
Okay, moving on.
>> You think we could,
Jim, should we look at the, let's look at the bylaws and the charter together and see if we can
revise our
bylaws accordingly.
We may be able to do that because if the Commission if the Charter doesn't say anything about
that kind of vacancy
I'm feeling like then we should be able to do it immediately.
Okay,
next I have
>> bylaws that I read,
and they
list a whole,
they really
have assignments for the chairman,
agent, the land use secretary.
And I happen
to know that the land use secretary doesn't do a lot of what's on her list.
And I believe there may be some union issues, and I just thought
perhaps
someone should have a conversation with
the town administrator before that
moves anywhere.
>> May already Section be in
six
staff and duties.
Yeah.
>> Office and duties. It may already be in place, but I don't, I can say it's not practiced.
I
just think it warrants conversation with
Eric
Anderson.
Next.
I just,
somewhere in there it says the, everything that gets posted on the county website has to go through the assistant county administrator.
First of all, I believe that's Amanda and she is the admin administrator.
And I don't and I also just I don't like the idea that that you assign
a specific
I mean, that that
function,
that name,
that job could change tomorrow.
I would think it would behoove us just to go,
I would say, get supposed to with
and
I I'm also big on, there should be more than one person that can do that.
It's not
>> it's not the end of the world. I'm sure these things have been posted. I just got
my
>> Okay.
Well, there is language to say that with the assistance of such staff as available,
the Recording Secretary shall, etcetera.
>> No, this is posting it. It refers to the assistant administrator somewhere.
The posting of notices and such.
Oh, okay. I don't know where. Section 16.
Section 16. I'm sorry.
So Jim?
Yes. I
>> don't know how the new website is constructed,
but I've worked on websites before where
a designated person can be given access to just a portion of the website
to do,
you know, posting minutes or
posting legal notices, but it would
be specific to the wetlands page or the
zoning page or something like that. But I'm not sure if the new website
constructed in them yet.
>> I've run across situations where,
you know, you you lock yourself in, only one person can do this.
Correct. Creates problems.
I have one more, which brought up Okay. Back in May, and I didn't get any traction then. 115
public hearings,
you speak it speaks of proponents and opponents.
So proponents speak and then
opponent.
My point is
Okay.
I'm not getting any audio,
Jim.
My
>> concern is this. I mean, public hearings
be somewhat avid adversarial to start with in their, you know, their neighbors.
Maybe somebody has a concern and they'd like to speak.
They're not an opponent.
I don't know why it has to be worded as that as such.
>> Well, it's a permit application,
the proponent
would be
first the person who is
applying for the permit. I think that this is kind of standard
parliamentary procedure to allow
the person who is
making the motion
in other words or making the the proposal
to speak first.
>> Well I think this people speaking on behalf of the application meaning maybe that could yeah
it may
include.
>> Right,
but I don't think it's the applicant but anyway I mean the applicant would be prior.
>> The applicant
would be the main proponent
of the Okay.
Then you have opponents.
>> Right. I brought this up, and you didn't like it then either.
>> It's Okay. Think that the intent here if you can find another way to put it, the idea is that
to make sure that both sides of the issue
are heard
and
that, as usual,
the
proponent
gets to go first because that's what you're going to be reacting to.
>> Right.
But from
in a meeting,
the chairman says, you know, opponents get up, and then, you know, opponents.
Are there any opponents? You have to get up and be an opponent to your neighbor's application.
All you really wanna say is, you know, you point out some minor concern.
That's my point.
>> Right.
It's
okay. I We don't
to make it too adversarial,
but it is a legal hearing.
And
maybe there's a way to put in there to allow
for
general comments maybe other than or
questions,
questions and comments
rather than cautioning it strictly in terms of debate.
>> Just
one
more issue They don't shut up.
We're you know, we've been doing this, and I I may have brought this up before. I think I brought it up at the planning and zoning meeting.
If it was a wetlands meeting,
refresh my memory, I'll stop. At some point,
question's gonna transition
away from Zoom meetings.
And people are gonna some people are gonna feel comfortable with that and some aren't. I think there's gonna be some sort of hybrid meeting,
where where some of the commission is in a in a room and others are participating.
And I think the bylaws are a good place to rest that, to allow it. Now
it doesn't have to be now.
I mean, something
that the commission thinks about. But I this is bylaws is where where you'd spell that process out.
It's gonna be interesting because
some people are ready to
go back in a room with others and others won't be for a long time.
And
we're gonna need to accommodate,
you know, the the diverse
opinions.
>> I think that is a point very well taken.
Developing some kind of hybrid model, the biologists wouldn't have to specify how it can be done, but we would have to allow for
the possibility of participation
in meetings without
being present.
And golly gee whiz, the US Congress is struggling with this same issue. Right, but I mean the business world must do this all
>> over. I mean it's
got to be a lot of
samples that work well. Yeah. Businesses have done this, you know, forever.
>> Gotta be Right.
But, you know, we have of course, we're we're a regulatory
commission
we have
legal obligations
about
you know
how to it to fulfill our regulations but
>> yeah it
could be addressed in bylaws and if there's a mean and it would
have to accommodate both public
applicants and all of their
advisors legal and engineering
advisors
and commissioners themselves
so
we have to have a way for participation
in the meeting
that's either
present
or
virtual.
>> And it's probably going to be forced anyway. Mean if you think about like the Americans with Disabilities Act,
we're required to accommodate
people with disabilities. I have to believe that as
COVID
nature
of things
change,
there's going to be regulations that address.
>> Right. How we we go about that. Yeah. I'm unable to
cast my ballot,
so I'm
entitled to use a mail in ballot automatically
without having to claim any further disability.
It's
somewhat analogous to that. So you're right there there is the question of actual
ability
to attend a meeting
and how do we accommodate an inability
to actually attend a meeting
>> I just I just wanted to throw it out there just for.
Let people think about it.
And it doesn't have to be.
Just thought the bylaws would be a good place for it, but.
Could be done at its own.
>> You're right unless unless something statutory comes up
you know if the legislature
or executive order
makes it part of regulations
then it wouldn't have to be in bylaws but I think the bylaws would be the best place
to address that
since you know all of our you know our meeting procedures or hearing procedures and all that
are in the bylaws
that would be the logical place
for any
modification of standard procedures.
Thank you.
>> Okay.
Any other comments on bylaws?
Okay. Our next meeting is scheduled for September 15, subject
to the need,
potential need for
a special meeting
if
we
need to act
on
the
let's see which application
was it. I guess it's the Korea application.
Yeah, 2021.
Could we set tentatively a date for a special meeting if needed
Hopefully with Megan back from vacation
but within the timeline.
Can somebody quick do the math on
June 10 plus ninety days?
September 8.
Thank you. So
before September 8.
Looks like September 1.
I forgot it's Labor Day, isn't it?
Labor Day is on you.
>> Labor Day is the seventh. Labor Day is the seventh, yeah.
Ninety days from when? June what?
June 10.
>> That'd be like September 8, isn't it? Or thereabouts? Yeah. Give her a good day.
>> Right, and of course our
regular meeting is deferred because of Labor Day.
How So. About the week before anyway?
>> I was gonna say the week of
August
31,
I'm gonna be out the week previously.
So
>> August 31 onward because there shouldn't be any meeting scheduled that week because that's the fifth Monday.
I don't know if we can do simultaneous
Zoom meetings or not. I don't know what our limitations are.
Nor do I.
So you're proposing August 31?
>> Either that or September 1. Either one of those I think would work for us.
>> Yeah, so Monday or Tuesday at week thirty six.
I'm open for either of those.
Other,
don't obviously can't speak for Megan,
but.
I don't see it. I'm looking at the TOM calendar and there's definitely nothing on for
August 31.
And there is nothing on for the evening of
Tuesday
September 1. So both of those would be open in terms of
not conflicting with anything in the town.
Any preferences?
>> I guess we probably ought to stick with Monday since that's our routine except for when it's not.
>> Right.
So
it's
only not our routine when something else prevents us.
So
why don't we pencil it in
potential special meeting
on nineone?
Oh, eightthirty one.
>> Eightthirty one, I'm sorry.
I mean that's that just gets it on our calendars if we need to have it then obviously we'll have to warn it and all that
in
due course
Hopefully that won't be an issue.
>> George, this is Linda. Yeah, Linda. I think you actually have to move it,
make a motion
to schedule the meeting so that it's on the record.
>> What if we don't need to have that meeting? Then you can cancel it. Okay.
Then I'll
take a motion to schedule a special meeting
for August
31.
So moved.
Thank you, Mr. Smith.
Do I have a second?
Ted seconds. Okay,
>> so motion by Ed Smith, second by Jed Larson to schedule a special meeting
for August
31,
7PM.
Roll call vote.
Mr. Smith?
Aye.
Mr. Larson?
Aye. Mr. Hallisey?
Aye.
>> And I
vote aye as well as for the motion carries four-zero-zero.
The final item on the agenda
would then be
a
motion to adjourn.
Ed Smith seconds.
>> Okay.
I didn't hear the actual motion. Who made the motion? Oh, I make a motion that we adjourn
okay
and a second to that motion
Jed seconds okay
>> so
moved and seconded to adjourn
non debatable so let's just vote by voice all in favor aye
motion carries unanimously
meeting stands adjourned
at
09:54
p